Hi, I'm Jessica, but the past year, a bit of a mission to explore how quantum computing
can change how we understand the environment, our data, and even ourselves.
It started with one big question.
How can we move beyond today's computing limits and create something more evolved?
That question led me to build MQBA, molecular quantum particle algorithm.
Later, I appeared with a powerful tool called MTQC, multi-target quantum compilation.
I didn't create MTQC, but I adapted it slightly to work with MQBA and make it scalable.
Together, they formed a corva system that blends quantum computing, GIS, molecular modeling,
and AI.
Let's start with the basics.
Classical computers use bits, zeros and ones.
Quantum computers use qubits, zero, one, or built at the same time.
That's called superposition.
There's also entanglement, when two qubits are linked.
Change one and the other reacts instantly, no matter how far apart they are.
These features allow us to solve complex problems faster than classical machines ever could.
I applied this to GIS, geographic information systems.
These platforms already pull a massive data from satellites, drones, radar, and sensors.
The classical systems struggle the process quickly, or put it in a real world context-fast enough to act.
Quantum GIS flips the script.
With quantum tools, I can model storm behavior, trap pollution, and predict environmental changes
all in real time, and across multiple possible outcomes.
It's like giving your weather model a quantum brain, one that sees multiple features at once.
Now let's talk about MQBA.
It stimulates how model kills scatter, bond, and react to environmental forces.
I didn't run these models in isolation.
I linked them to geography, live terrain, ecosystems, and weather clients.
To scale this up, I used MTQC, a compiler that lets you execute many quantum models in parallel.
I slightly tweaked it to fit MQBA's needs.
The classical system handles prep and post-processing.
The quantum layer runs the pattern discovery optimization.
Grover's algorithm helps locate patterns quickly.
Thor's helps simplify quantum outlets.
Together, they power a hybrid system for environmental simulation.
I used Google early on for rapid prototyping.
It wasn't perfect, but it let me test fast and switch between quantum backends quickly.
My data source was varied.
I've worked with QM9 for molecular structures, NASA satellite light our data,
environmental logs, public, physical records,
pollution data tied to geographic locations.
Each data set that's cleaned classically
then passed through quantum learning models,
like quantum classifiers, kernel models, or auto-encodes.
I pulled the results back to classical space visualization and interpretation.
Interpretation is key.
So I built a GPT-based assistant, my quantum fluent AI.
It reads raw circuit output and explains them in plain English.
When I'm modeling how fossil fuels shift in earthquake,
or if I'm modeling how rainfall changes urban air chemistry,
my assistant can make those results clear and usable.
I also post this visually.
I passed MQBA outputs into Blunder to create three demolecular meshes.
Then I processed those model kills using quantum node circuits.
I visualized the behavior of block spheres
and mapped out entanglements as interactive 3D geometry.
The hardest part?
Particle scattering.
I used a hybrid quantum method to simulate how particle scatter
without changing the speed.
Even with hardware noise and decoherence,
I was able to get useful predictive results.
So basically I went from tracking storms
to modeling the birth of model kills.
Every part of this process blended quantum,
classical and AI tools to interpret,
simulate and refine what we see in nature.
The result?
Real-time pipelines for smarter environmental modeling.
A framework that can be deployed today
by government defense or research labs.
And now I'm wrapping it into a full AI interface on my site,
jessie.chepp.
Right now it's just a project showcase,
but it's actively becoming a real working tool.
Lots of moving parts.
Lots and lots of provisioning.
Lots of moving models back and forth.
And yeah, it's expensive and conversant,
but it's happening.
It's happening now.
The final version will include GPT,
BERT, MQPA, MTQC,
interactive search generators.
Hugging face, transformer models,
and all the visual quantum tools I've described.
So yeah, it's been quite a year
and I've just getting started.
Thank you guys so much for listening.
And special thanks to Dr. Vivian Sather,
Dr. Eric Larson, Dr. Jacqueline Chen,
and Dr. Jessie Zara Zalva for your trust,
support, and belief in this vision.
I can't wait to show you guys what's next.
Let's go make some quantum noise.